A Guide to the Papers of William Faulkner 1925-1962
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
1925-1962
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
9817-a
34 items
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Deposit of Mrs. Jill Summers through Linton Massey on March 22, 1974.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in three series I. Manuscripts. II. Correspondence. III. Miscelaneous Items.
Contents List
- Manuscripts
  - TMs (Carbon) A Fable[beginning at page 189 of the printed work], 12 p. on 12 l. 1934-1935
  - TMs A Fable with holograph notes and household financial accounts on verso of each page, 4 p. on 2 l. 1943-1944
  - TMs Rough draft with holograph corrections of the funeral sermon for Mammy Caroline Barr, Oxford, Mississippi, February, 1940, 1940, 2 p. on 2 l.; photocopy only
  - TMs Segment from Delta Autumn from Go Down, Moses 1941-1942
  - TMs Chapter I, part 2, The Fire and the Hearth from Go Down, Moses, 1 p. on 1 l. 1941-1942
  - TMs Chapter III, part 1, The Fire and the Hearth from Go Down, Moses, 32 p. on 24 l. (24 Recto, 8 Verso) 1941-1942
  - TMs The Old People, part 1, with holograph corrections from 1941-1942
  - TMs The Old People, part 2, with holograph corrections from Go down, Moses, 4 p. on 2 l. 1941-1942
  - TMs (carbon) Early trial version of Abraham's Children, finally published as The Peasants in The Hamlet, 4 p. on 4 l. 1926-1929
  - TMs (carbon) Early trial version of Abraham's Children, finally published as The Peasants in The Hamlet, 13 p. on 13 l. 1926-1929
  - TMs Early trial version of Abraham's Children, finally published as The Peasants in The Hamlet, 9 p. on 9 l. 1926-1929
  - TMs Early trial version of Abraham's Children, finally published as The Peasants in The Hamlet, 48 p. on 48 l. 1926-1929
  - TMs Early trial version of Abraham's Children, finally published as The Peasants in The Hamlet, 3 p. on 3 l. 1926-1929
  - TMs Early trial version of Father Abraham, later published as the short story Spotted Horses and as The Peasants in The Hamlet, 6 p. on 6 l. 1926-1929
  - TMs Early trial version of Father Abraham, later published as the short story Spotted Horses and as The Peasants in The Hamlet, 56 p. (54 recto, 2 verso) on 54 l. 1926-1929
  - TMs (carbon) Early trial version of The Peasants in The Hamlet, 59 p. on 59 l. 1926-1929
  - TMs Segment from The Peasants in The Hamlet, 1 p. on 1 l. 1926-1929
  - TMs with carbon Early trial version of the short story Spotted Horses also published later as The Peasants in The Hamlet, 17 p. on 17 l. ca. 1925
  - TMs (carbon) Early trial version of the short story Spotted Horses also published later as The Peasants in The Hamlet, 22 p. on 22 l. ca. 1925
  - TMs Early trial version of the short story Spotted Horses also published later as The Peasants in The Hamlet, 32 p. on 32 l. ca. 1925
  - TMs Segments from The Mansion with holograph corrections, parts of Chapters 6, 14 and 15, 26 p. on 13 l. 1959-1960
  - TMs Pages with holograph corrections from Chapter 16 of The Mansion, 2 p. on 1 l. 1959-1960
  - TMs (carbon) Unpublished short story The Hog Pawn later used as an episode in Chapter 14 of The Mansion, 30 p. (26 recto, 4 verso)on 26 l. ca. 1952
  - TMs Trial version of The Reivers Chapter 4, 8 p. on 8 l. 1961-1962
  - TMs (carbon) Requiem for a Nun with holograph corrections, Act II, Scenes 1,2,3, and Act III, Scene 1, 218 p.(187 Recto, 31 Verso) on 187 l. ca. 1951
  - TMs with carbon Statement for press release regarding integration, 4 p. on 4 l. 1955 Sep 6
  - AMs Unidentified fragment of an essay beginning Recently in an article concerned with the high cost of medicine...., 1 p. on 1 l. n.d.
  - AMs Unidentified fragment of an essay beginning Since the organizers of the B. M. C. ...., 1 p. on 1 l. n.d.
  - TMs/AMs Unidentified fragment of an essay beginning Money and the complex records of it...., 2 p. on 2 l. n.d.
- Correspondence
  - TL/TMs Drafta of a letter to The Daily Progress, Charlottesville, Va., regarding Interstate 64; on verso of first page is an unidentified fragment of a manuscript beginning Buster...and suggested she was going to....; and on verso of last two pages is a part of Chapter 14 with holograph corrections of The Mansion, 6 p. on 3 l. ca. 1960
  - TL (carbon) William Faulkner to The Commercial Appeal regarding racial equality, 26 p. on 23 l. n.d.
  - TL William Faulkner to Alexander Rives with holograph additions beginning Will pay 42500 dollars for house...., 1 p. on 1 l. n.d.
- Miscellaneous
  - William Faulkner's holograph map of Yoknapawtawpha County, 1 p. on 1 l. n.d.
  - Possible trial holograph map for endpaper of Viking Portable Faulkner and Absalom, Absalom, 1 p. on 1 l. n.d.